[
    {
        "question": "What are Catalonia, Andalusia, Cantabria, Galicia?",
        "answer": "Regions in Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European country is divided into areas called Cantons?",
        "answer": "Switzerland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What large island is the most western point of land in Alaska?",
        "answer": "Attu Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to the oceanside city Myrtle Beach?",
        "answer": "South Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many South American Countries does the equator pass through?",
        "answer": "Three"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lanzarote is part of which island group?",
        "answer": "The Canaries"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Irish city is Shannon airport?",
        "answer": "Shannon"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country is the Simpson Desert located?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which stretch of water is Europe`s most northern boundary?",
        "answer": "Arctic Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is the European Court of Justice?",
        "answer": "Luxembourg"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano `Pelee`?",
        "answer": "Martinique"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano `Santorini`?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano `Popocatepetl`?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where would you find the active volcano `Erebus`?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano `Nevado del Ruiz`?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano `Lamington`?",
        "answer": "Papua New Guinea"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which river is the city of Mandalay situated?",
        "answer": "Irrawaddy River"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which river is the Asian city of Mandalay situated?",
        "answer": "Irrawaddy River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kiev is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Ukraine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kiev is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Ukraine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the smallest Canadian province?",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European city is known as Auld Reekie?",
        "answer": "Edinburgh"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Oaxaca, Mexico, Christmas Eve is also called `Night of` what vegetable?",
        "answer": "Radish"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what world capital will you find Ho Hoan Kiem, the Lake of the Restored Sword?",
        "answer": "Hanoi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the British Virgin Islands?",
        "answer": "Road Town"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which district of the United Kingdom is Scaffel Pike, England`s highest peak, found?",
        "answer": "The Lake District"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which peninsula is shared by Portugal and Spain?",
        "answer": "Iberian peninsula"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is often mistakenly referred to as the `Lost City of the Incas`?",
        "answer": "Machu Picchu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which desert is the driest on earth?",
        "answer": "Atacama"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which precious stones are found in the Namib desert in Africa?",
        "answer": "Diamonds"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river runs through the Grand Canyon?",
        "answer": "Colorado River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Kosovo?",
        "answer": "Pristina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the strait of water that separates the two main islands of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "Cook Strait"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Baton Rouge is located on the shores of what river?",
        "answer": "Mississippi River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Galveston, Mobile and Tampa are all located on the shores of what body of water?",
        "answer": "Gulf of Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Florida island was known by Spanish explorers as `Long Island`?",
        "answer": "Key Largo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state`s official song is `On the Banks of the Wabash, Far Away`?",
        "answer": "Indiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Great Sand Dunes National Monument?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the longest road tunnel in North America?",
        "answer": "Anton Anderson Memorial Tunnel -- Located in Alaska, it stretches nearly 2.5 miles. It is also a railway tunnel, built in 1943 to carry supplies during World War II."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest country in the world made up of solely islands?",
        "answer": "Indonesia -- The nation includes roughly 17,500 islands, of which about 7,000 are inhabited. With more than 735,000 square miles of land in total, it is the16th-largest country by land area."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where would you find the Nazca Lines?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which major cape is named for the Portuguese word for `needles`?",
        "answer": "Cape Agulhas -- Cape of Good Hope is often mistaken as the southernmost point of Africa; however, Cape Agulhas is located about 90 miles southeast."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the former home of naturalist John Muir?",
        "answer": "California -- Through his activism in the late 19th and early 20th centuries, he brought the preservation of wilderness into public consciousness and founded the Sierra Club."
    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage of the London Underground is actually underground?",
        "answer": "45% -- The tube network stretches for 249 miles, links together 270 stations, and uses more than 4100 trains to transport London`s population."
    },
    {
        "question": "`The Big Easy` is the nickname for what city?",
        "answer": "New Orleans"
    },
    {
        "question": "What modern city is situated near Mount Vesuvius?",
        "answer": "Naples"
    },
    {
        "question": "What island is located in The Bay of Naples?",
        "answer": "Capri"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. state is closest to Africa?",
        "answer": "Maine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nova Scotia is Latin for what?",
        "answer": "New Scotland"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Catedral de Sal, a cathedral carved entirely out of salt, is located in what country?",
        "answer": "Colombia"
    }
]